RG 045, State Revenue Task Force
Connecticut State Library
State Revenue Task Force records
1969-1971
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Revenue Task Force
3 cubic feet
The State Revenue Task Force was appointed pursuant to Special Act 274 of the 1969 Session of the General Assembly for the purpose of preparing recommendations for a revised Connecticut tax structure. The Task Force received suggestions and heard testimony from many government, community and business leaders, and it commissioned and studied a series of special reports on various aspects of the subject.
RG045
1971-002
Historical Note
The State Revenue Task Force was appointed pursuant to Special Act 274 of the 1969 Session of the General Assembly for the purpose of preparing recommendations for a revised Connecticut tax structure. It first met in the State Capitol on September 9, 1969, and adopted its report at a final meeting on January 21, 1971. Frazar B. Wilde was chair and Murray Drabkin served as its full-time director. The Task Force received suggestions and heard testimony from many government, community and business leaders, and it commissioned and studied a series of special reports on various aspects of the subject. Hearings were held in several major cities in addition to the regular meetings in the Capitol, most of which were open to the public.
Scope and Content
This record group contains minutes of meetings, a summary of recommendations, the final report, unpublished studies and memoranda, statements prepared for hearings, sound recordings of public heaerings, a general file and an administrative file.
Related Material
RG 047, Special Tax Commission, 1933 - 1935
RG 077, Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy, 1982-1983
RG 086, Governor's Commission on Tax Reform, 1972
RG 087, Connecticut Tax Study Commission, 1966 - 1967
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Revenue Task Force
Persons:
Drabkin, Murray; Wilde, Fazar Bullard
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Revenue Task Force -- Records and correspondence; Revenue -- Connecticut; Taxation -- Connecticut; Taxation -- Research -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Minutes; Reports; Sound recordings
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1969-1971
  - 1. Minutres of meetings, 1969 September 9-1971 January 21 (Box 1)
    Arranged chronologically.
  - 2. Summary of recommendations, 1971 January 26 (Box 1)
    Inculudes copies of the transmittal letter to the Governor, the summary of recommendations (16 pp.), the related press release, the text of the Chairman's speech, and a note on the personal income tax.
  - 3. Final report, 1971 February 11 (Box 1)
    Original typed copy (possibly for photo-offset) of the final report, with transmittal letter signed by the Chairman, table of contents, text (92 pages) and appendices (approximately 100 pages).
  - 4. Unpublished studies and memoranda, 1979 (Box 1)
    - See, Edmund M. and Sanford Neiman. Fee structure of the State of Connecticut. (Box 1)
    - Gravlin, Leslie M. State grant-in-aid programs supplementing those listed in "State Aid to Local Government in Connecticut - A Reference Guide to the General Statutes," published by the Insitite of Public Service, University of Connecticut, March 1970. (Box 1)
    - Hinrichs, Harley H. Comments on future developments of Federal grants-in-aid and projected aid to Connecticut. (Box 1)
    - Netzer, Dick. State water pollution charges (a supplement to "User charge revenue in Connecticut: Practice and prospects"). (Box 1)
    - No author. Off-track betting and State operated lotteries. (Box 1)
    - Gravlin, Leslie M. Service charges on private tax-exempt property. (Box 1)
    - Gravlin, Leslie M. The personal property tax. (Box 1)
    - Netzer, Dick. Tuition and scholarship possibilities in higher education: Some global estimates. (Box 1)
    - Ainsworth, Kenneth G. State-local fiscal relationships in Connecticut. (Box 1)
    - Ainsworth, Kenneth G. Alternative formulas used to distribute state aid to local jurisdictions. (Box 1)
  - 5 Statements prepared for hearings, April 10, 1970 and June 9, 1970, 1 looseleaf binder (Box 1)
    The texts of statements delivered or prepared for presentation to the public hearings held in Hartford. Those prepared for the april 10 hearing are preceded by copies of letters of invitation, a list of speakers, and the text of Chairman Wilde's opening remarks.
  - 6. Sound recordings of public hearings, 1970 May-June (Box 2)
    Gray Audagraph (and one Soundscriber) discs containing the proceedings of public hearings in the communities listed below, together iwth the lists of participants, the texts of some statements and other related materials.
    - Waterbury, 1970 May 14 (Box 2)
    - New London, 1970 May 19 (Box 2)
    - Torrington, 1970 May 21 (Box 2)
    - Willimantic, 1970 May 27 (Box 2)
    - Bridgeport, 1970 June 2 (Box 2)
    - New Haven, 1970 June 4 (Box 2)
    - Hartford, 1970 June 9 (Box 2)
  - 7.; General file, 1969-1971
    Correspondence, memoranda, working papers and reference materials.
    - Complaints (Tax structure) (Box 2)
    - Connecticut Association of Assessing Officers, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Connecticut Conference of Mayors (Box 2)
    - Connecticut inheritance tax -- Jantscher (Box 2)
    - Corporation business tax (Box 2)
    - Corporation business tax -- Banks (Box 2)
    - Expenditure & revenue projections (Box 2)
    - Expenditure projections (State Departments) (Box 2)
    - Fee Structure of the State of Connecticut. See, Edmund M. and Sanford Neiman (Box 2)
    - General fund deficit (Box 2)
    - Highway user taxes (Box 2)
    - Incidence of Connecticut state & local taxes & expenditures -- Eapen (Box 2)
    - Interstate fiscal comparisons -- Morss (Box 3)
    - Insurance company taxes (Box 3)
    - Interstate fiscal comparisons (Box 3)
    - Lead men (Box 3)
    - Materials distributed to task force (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 3)
    - Off-track betting, lotteries (Box 3)
    - Open space taxation (Box 3)
    - Payment in lieu of taxes program (Box 3)
    - Personal income tax - Circuit breaker (Box 3)
    - Personal income tax (Estimates) (Box 3)
    - Personal income tax IRS data (Box 3)
    - Personal income tax -- Other states (Box 3)
    - Personal income tax (Task force proposals) (Box 3)
    - Personal income tax -- Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Personal property tax (Box 4)
    - Personal property tax -- 1969 town list with ueld estimates prepared by State Tax Department (Box 4)
    - Population, employment & income in Connecticut. Ainsworth, 1970 July (Box 4)
    - Positions of local government (Box 4)
    - Positions of organizations (Business, civic, etc.) (Box 4)
    - Property tax (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire & replies -- Towns and cities, 1970 March (Box 4)
    - Real estate conveyance tax (Box 4)
    - Regional task force hearings (Box 4)
    - Revenue and Expenditure Projections for the State and Local Governments of Connecticut, 1970-1080. Kenneth G. Ainsworht, Elliott R. Morss (Box 4)
    - Revenue estimate -- CPEC, 1970 April (Box 5)
    - Revenue estimates consequences of various proposals (Box 5)
    - Revenue estimates general fund (Box 5)
    - Sales and use tax (Box 5)
    - Service charges on private tax exempt property (Box 5)
    - State and Local Revenue Projections -- Ainsworth, 1970 July (Box 5)
    - State grants-in-aid programs (Box 5)
    - State grants-in-aid -- Block grants (Box 5)
    - State tax studies -- Bibliography (Box 5)
    - Task force actions -- Recap sheets (Box 5)
    - Task force agendas (Box 5)
    - Task force budget (Box 5)
    - Task force clippings (Box 5)
    - Task force consultants (Box 5)
    - Tax force -- Correspondence with members (Box 5)
    - Task force -- Legal opinions (Box 5)
    - Task force -- Letters of complaint (Box 5)
    - Task force -- Mateiral forwarded from Mr. Wilde's office (Box 5)
    - Task force meeting notices (Box 6)
    - Task force -- SA 274 -- Rosters, etc. (Box 6)
    - Task force -- Subcommittees (Box 6)
    - Tax collections (Box 6)
    - Tax exemptions -- Elderly (Box 6)
    - User charges -- Tuition (Box 6)
    - User charges -- Water pollution (Box 6)
    - Utilities taxes (Box 6)
  - 8. Administrative file, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, notes and related materials relating primarliy to reimbursement of consultants' expenses, editing and reproduction of studies, travel and meeting arrangements, etc.
    - Ainsworth, Kenneth G., Professor -- Consultant (Box 6)
    - Drabkin, Murray -- Director (Box 6)
    - Eapen, A. Thomas (Box 6)
    - Hinrichs, Harley H. -- Consultant (Box 6)
    - Jantscher, Gerald R. (Box 6)
    - Jolles, Ira H. -- Consultant (Box 6)
    - Morss, Elliott M. -- Consultant (Box 6)
    - Netzer, Dick (Box 6)
    - See, Edmund and Sanford Neiman (Box 6)
    - Smith, Theodore Reynolds (Box 6)
    - Wilde, Frazar B. -- Chairman (Box 6)
  - 9. Secretary's record book, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
    Notebook kept by Mrs. Joan Kemler, containing minutes, notes, correspondence, newspaper clippings.